Software Engineer

San Francisco, CA

Focused, passionate, and technically competent. An excellent communicator; willing and able to engage people at different skill and leadership levels. Experienced in a broad array of disciplines to include; foreign languages, software development, data modeling, performing arts , blogging, fitness, public speaking, and teaching. An active member of the local tech community, helping to plan, organize, and present in local tech events. An avid learner with a voracious appetite for knowledge. Most importantly, a friendly human-being with a genuine desire to help others.

WORK EXPERIENCE

NATIONAL SECURITY AGENCY

 $Software\ Developer/Analyst$

Jan, 2012 - May, 2016

Tasked with providing timely and accurate intelligence to various stakeholders. Granted a unique assignment amongst over 2000 military personnel to be a full-time software developer; working alongside National Security Agency Mathematicians, Computer Scientists, and Engineers, to create new software applications and data pipelines for intelligence analysts.

US NAVY

Cryptologic Technician Interpretive

Jun, 2010 - May, 2016

Intelligence gathering and analysis as a Mandarin Chinese linguist.

EDUCATION

DEFENSE LANGUAGE INSTITUTE

Associate's Degree - Mandarin Chinese

 $Jul,\ 2010-Dec,\ 2011$

Graduated 2+/2 from elite military language program with an accredited Associate's Degree.

CITY COLLEGE OF SAN FRANCISCO

Transfer - Cognitive Science

Sep, 2016 - Current

The following are classes I have taken or am currently taking at CCSF prior to transferring to Berkeley for Cognitive Science

- CS231 Advanced Python Programming
- CS 110B C++ Programming
- CS 212 iPhone Programming (Swift)
- PHIL 12A Symbolic Logic
- PHIL 25C Modern Philosophy through Kant
- MATH 100A Calculus
- CS260A/P Linux System Administration

PROJECTS

GOFISH

Sole Developer

Jun, 2014 - May, 2016

A text parser that has so far processed over four million lines of data and saved analysts over three-thousand man-hours worth of work per year. Written over several months while working as an analyst. Led to a Joint Service Achievement Medal and placement into an official software development role.

UNNAMED PROJECT

Software Developer/ Military-Civilian liason/ SME

Jun, 2014 - May, 2016

A collaborative project between DoD civilian leadership and military personnel designed to store, share, and analyze information for military analysts and their customers. Worked as a project lead, software developer, subject-matter expert, and military-civilian liason. Contributed greatly to the complete restructuring of a 60-person organization as a result of massive increase in analyst productivity.

ref-id: DJ2-2016-00904